<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jake Larkin</title>
    <description>This is Jake Larkin&#39;s personal website and blog.
</description>
    <link>http://jakelarkin.co/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://jakelarkin.co/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2015 23:38:32 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2015 23:38:32 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Your Side Projects Don&#39;t Suck</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;About one month into any new job and you already begin to get the hang of your responsibilities and daily routine. You are supposed to do this on Mondays, and supposed to do that on Tuesdays, and then usually you meet with so-and-so to talk about yada-yada on Wednesdays. Even at a fast paced company like a startup, you become ingrained in your core responsibilities and you lose pieces of the excitement that existed during the first few weeks. Not only do you feel less fulfilled and challenged, but the company loses its ability to explore and learn from a new set of eyes or new topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This doesn’t need to be the case. How do you fix it? Side projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-a-side-project&quot;&gt;What is a side project?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A project being conducted at work or outside of work that does not directly relate to the growth of the company you are involved with. They certainly may co-exist in the same industry, but the side project is outside of the daily routine of your company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;whos-doing-it&quot;&gt;Who’s doing it?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good question. If I were you, I probably would not take advice from a small app development company without first doing some research. It may shock you, but even large corporations are getting into the world of side projects. Some are hosting weekend hack-a-thons or even after hour building sessions, both of which are reserved for working on strictly side-projects (no company work). Google even has a policy in place that 20% of your working hours (not overtime) can be spent on projects that you want to work on, even if they are completely unrelated to the company. Apple, Microsoft, Spotify, Uber and many more are building company cultures that allow employees to work on side projects. It’s the reason Gmail and Google Drive exist. Heck, even the Post-it-Note was started as a side project at 3M.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;where-do-you-begin&quot;&gt;Where do you begin?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Side projects come in all shapes and sizes. Of course, your company might have an inherent interest in making the side project a success, but this is certainly not a limitation of the possibilities. Side projects can be stupid. They don’t need to serve an immediate purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;start-now&quot;&gt;Start Now&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest piece of advice on how to begin is simple – just do it. Seriously. If there is something that sounds exciting to learn about, grab a few co-workers and explain it to them. Explain why you think it would be exciting and get cranking. Failure is inevitable with side projects, so quit worrying about what happens when your idea sucks. Even if you know your idea is not the greatest, the outcome is not the goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;keep-it-simple&quot;&gt;Keep it Simple&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Side projects are not complicated by nature. A small idea that gets executed during a few extra hours at work means that it shouldn’t be complicated. You still have to accomplish your core responsibilities, so side projects move in small increments. You can safely ignore all the questions that you ask yourself on bigger projects. There is no need to worry about, “This thing won’t scale” or “How in the world will this ever make money?” Decide which core elements are needed to bring the idea to life and make those happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;forget-scale&quot;&gt;Forget Scale&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the absolute toughest aspect of side projects. The society we find ourselves in now thinks that it has the ability to measure opportunity, but the truth is – you can’t. There are so many variables that go into the success or failure of an idea that you could never listen to a 10 minute pitch about an idea and have the slightest clue about its outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the start, you need to forget about scale. Forget about how you will measure the success of your idea. These do not matter with side projects. You work on a side project because it makes you happy. You have a connection to the idea that should not be stopped by some &lt;a href=&quot;http://insurancethoughtleadership.com/swot-analysis-swot-analysis/&quot;&gt;SWOT analysis&lt;/a&gt;. A side project should only get bigger when you want it to get bigger and never before then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;why&quot;&gt;Why?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are reading this and are an employee, this is important. At some point, you are likely going to explain why you spent 3 hours coding a website that doesn’t actually do anything or you made a financial model of an industry that your company has nothing to do with. As I mentioned before, the outcome of the project is not always the purpose of the project, but I can’t promise that your boss will understand this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;you-run-the-show&quot;&gt;You Run the Show&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a side project, you become the boss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea is yours and you run the operation. When things change, embrace the changes. Work with a team of people who truly want to work on the project and nobody that is simply escaping their core responsibilities. This will the project owner first hand experience at running a team and delegating tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;its-like-recess-for-adults&quot;&gt;It’s Like Recess for Adults&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think back to your elementary days when the 45 minutes following lunch was the best time of the day. Not only because you weren’t working on your school work (i.e. core responsibilities) but you were learning new things. Of course, in 5th grade, new things might have been how to jump rope, or how to build a fort out of mud or even how to kiss your first girlfriend, but the implication is the same. A side project is like recess for adults. When you remove constraints, your exploration brain kicks in and real learning begins. You can make a dozen mistakes and not be ashamed. You can dig into an entire new industry and learn everything about it. You take your mind off of the your core responsibilities and in turn, you may even learn how to do them better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;it-helps-business&quot;&gt;It Helps Business&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Side projects force you to learn about a field that you have no knowledge about. To expose new areas that are ripe for innovation. To bring to life ideas that would have otherwise remained in a notebook. Even if the side project is deemed a failure, everyone involved is now slightly more informed about the industry they were peering into and this will likely come up further down the road. In fact, it may even help your current company pivot into a whole new field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;designlis-projects&quot;&gt;Designli’s Projects&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Designli, we fully embrace side projects. First and foremost, we are an app development company, but we all share a love in creating cool, new products. We launched our first two projects a few months ago, &lt;a href=&quot;www.yourappmvp.com&quot;&gt;YourAppMVP&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;www.fixedpricewp.com&quot;&gt;FixedPriceWP&lt;/a&gt; as purely afterhour projects that we thought we exciting enough to release and watch grow. We have two new projects that are currently in the works that we are very excited to share as soon as they are live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-your-company-can-support-side-projects&quot;&gt;How Your Company Can Support Side Projects&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good start is to block off a portion of the work week and give your employees creative freedom. Let them work on something that has been bugging them for weeks. An irking frustration that they want to solve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;make-sure-to-not-assign-value-to-any-project-over-another-each-employee-has-the-need-to-express-their-own-abilities-and-explore-uncharted-grounds-for-themselves-do-not-attempt-to-measure-this-with-any-data&quot;&gt;1. Make sure to not assign value to any project over another. Each employee has the need to express their own abilities and explore uncharted grounds for themselves. Do not attempt to measure this with any data.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;allow-projects-to-be-on-going-if-the-crowd-agrees-that-a-project-is-exciting-let-it-keep-going-give-them-more-time-to-work-on-it-and-possibly-a-small-budget-of-funds-to-play-around-with&quot;&gt;2. Allow projects to be on-going. If the crowd agrees that a project is exciting, let it keep going. Give them more time to work on it and possibly a small budget of funds to play around with.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These two acts will display your level of trust and remove fear at the exact same time. Both imperative for a successful “side-project” culture. Have any questions or advice for generating cooler side projects? Let us know!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 12:33:39 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://jakelarkin.co/blog/update/2015/07/01/side-projects.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jakelarkin.co/blog/update/2015/07/01/side-projects.html</guid>
        
        <category>Startups</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Recipe For a Rockstar App Launch</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So you’ve decided to build an app? Congratulations! You’ve decided to be a contributor instead of simply a consumer, and we love that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of September 2014, there were over 1.3 million apps on the Apple iOS app store. This number is growing at a nonlinear rate with over 300,000 apps added last year. For the math whizzes, that’s over 820 apps a day. The Google Play store is a similar story with 1.3 million apps in July of 2014. These are huge directories, how are you going to stand out from the crowd?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not to frighten you further, but the statistics tell an even more disturbing tale. The iOS store and its plethora of apps are nearly all free. In fact, 56% can be downloaded for no cost and another 36% charge a maximum of $3 per download. This leaves a staggering 8% charging more than $3 for an app. Again, the Google Play store has similar results with 72% being free to download and only 6% charging a premium of over $3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surprised? How about this: 63% of the apps used daily today are different than those being used daily only a year prior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, these statistics are a bit vague in their true meaning. On one hand, they show that the app industry is booming. It’s exponential. Remember, 820 apps are added to the market daily! That means by the time you’ve reached this point, an app has been submitted to the app store. The global app market is a $45 million industry and expected to grow 30-40% in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, you should be able to recognize that there is a fundamental feature that all successful apps must explicitly demonstrate: the ability to stand out. This is what I want to advise you on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;pre-development&quot;&gt;Pre-Development&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Designli, we talk about apps all day long, like it’s our job. Wait, it is our job. Anyway, we’ve seen apps make a huge splash on the app market and we’ve seen some fizzle out just after development. We are here to help make certain that the later doesn’t happen. The honest truth is that making an app as successful as Instagram or Snapchat requires a lot of work, but usually follows a similar core recipe (with a lot of ups and downs in between).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am going to make the huge assumption that you’ve already completed the design stage of this process including a logo and screens of the app. This topic is worthy of an entirely different post saved for a later date. For now, you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gv.com/design/&quot;&gt;reference&lt;/a&gt; the gang at Google, I hear that they know a thing or two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;talk-to-users&quot;&gt;Talk to Users&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important person behind an app is not the developer, investor or even you, it’s your consumer. Go out there, and make absolutely certain that someone is going to use this thing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;create-social-media-pages&quot;&gt;1. Create Social Media Pages&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, you want to consider which accounts will fit your app’s community. Most will require a Facebook and a Twitter to communicate with followers, but only some need an Instagram, Tumblr, Vine, etc. For a little advice on which accounts to make, listen to the most prevalent generation’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/backchannel/a-teenagers-view-on-social-media-1df945c09ac6&quot;&gt;opinion on each&lt;/a&gt;. The most important aspect of this decision relates to if you can actually &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.hubspot.com/blog/tabid/6307/bid/29272/5-Awesome-Examples-of-Engaging-Social-Media-Campaigns.aspx&quot;&gt;engage your customers&lt;/a&gt; using this social platform. If the answer is no, then forget about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;make-a-landing-page&quot;&gt;2. Make a Landing Page&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A landing or splash page is just a fancy way of saying a short and sweet website that describes your app, displays your name, logo and a few screens. The most important aspect of this is allowing your user to contact you with questions and sign up for a mailing list (Call it “Pre-Beta List”, people love that). Below is an example of a landing page and a few resources to dig into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; margin-bottom:50px; margin-top:50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/tn.png&quot; style=&quot;max-width:80%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://land-book.com/&quot;&gt;Land-Book&lt;/a&gt;: Product landing pages gallery.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unbounce.com&quot;&gt;Unbounce&lt;/a&gt;: Build, publish and push A/B test pages without IT&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.launchrock.com/&quot;&gt;Launchrock&lt;/a&gt;: A site builder dedicated to early user acquisition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sell-this-thing-like-it-exists&quot;&gt;3. Sell This Thing Like It Exists&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though you are in the pre-development stage, sell this product like it exists. Share it with anyone you’ve ever talked to. Friends, family, enemies, 1st grade teacher, whoever will listen. Practice your &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.inc.com/guides/2010/05/mastering-business-elevator-pitch.html&quot;&gt;60 second pitch&lt;/a&gt; and master the art of “What’s the problem and how will this solve it.” At this point, acquiring users is critical so discuss how the app is going to help them, don’t waste their time with how you are going to make money off of them. Walk them through scenarios, “Imagine you are…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider rewarding early adopters with cool things, including free subscriptions, free t-shirts, free promotion, whatever people respond to! Consider trying a campaign on &lt;a href=&quot;http://untorch.com/&quot;&gt;untorch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Record all of this feedback. Iterate. And seek more feedback. This can be done through surveys, phone calls, or even related &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/advertising&quot;&gt;Facebook Advertising&lt;/a&gt; and the likes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;development-time&quot;&gt;Development Time&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you have decided to utilize &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.designli.co/&quot;&gt;Designli&lt;/a&gt; to build your app (hooray) or another app development resource, the development process will require tons of iterations and fixes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;beta-launch&quot;&gt;Beta-Launch&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To maximize this process, assemble a variety of beta testers who are either your friends, or early adopters of the app, which can be offered as one of the best rewards for their support. Be careful to select people who are afraid of sharing honest feedback, even negative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;keep-in-touch&quot;&gt;4. Keep In Touch&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remain in good touch with anyone interested in the app. They are curious what you are doing; tell them. And keep those updates beautiful and useful, whether through email campaigns or social media updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; margin-bottom:50px; margin-top:50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/robinhood.png&quot; style=&quot;max-width:80%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mailchimp.com/&quot;&gt;Mailchimp&lt;/a&gt;: Send 12,000 emails to 2,000 subscribers for free.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hootsuite.com/&quot;&gt;Hootsuite&lt;/a&gt;: Share social media updates with all of your platforms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;test-your-app---a-lot&quot;&gt;5. Test Your App - A Lot&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a pivotal step. You do not want to ship an app that is full of bugs, because you will lose customers and trust. You can utilize some of these powerful tools:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uservoice.com/&quot;&gt;UserVoice&lt;/a&gt;: Easy feedback widget for beta users&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://try.crashlytics.com/&quot;&gt;Crashlytics&lt;/a&gt;: Fix those nagging bugs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vueanalytics.co/&quot;&gt;Vue&lt;/a&gt;: Determine who is using and leaving your app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;display-feedback&quot;&gt;6. Display Feedback&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use the feedback you’ve been given and display it to the masses. This can be on your landing page, through your emails and social campaigns or through more formal techniques. Try to recruit a handful of beta testers to drop positive and honest feedback on the iTunes or Google Play store. These stores have algorithms that favor highly enjoyed apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;lets-launch-this-thing&quot;&gt;Let’s Launch This Thing&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; margin-bottom:50px; margin-top:50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/dance.gif&quot; style=&quot;max-width:80%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day has come that you’ve been waiting for. The world is about to see your baby and fall in love with it just as you did. Let’s make sure that this holds true. Alert your pre-beta users via an interesting email campaign, incentivizing them to download the app immediately by setting deadlines or offering free credits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;direct-downloads&quot;&gt;7. Direct Downloads&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to make it incredibly easy to download the app. Try a service like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linktexting.com/&quot;&gt;LinkTexting&lt;/a&gt; to get users directly downloading your app via text messages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;exposure-the-kind-safe-for-work&quot;&gt;8. Exposure (the kind safe for work)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point you may be exhausted of pitching your app, but now is your time to shine. It’s time to flood the internet with news that your app is live. Try these resources to post your app:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.producthunt.com/&quot;&gt;Product Hunt&lt;/a&gt;: Curation of the best new products, every day.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://angel.co/&quot;&gt;Angellist&lt;/a&gt;: Where the world meets startups.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://betalist.com/&quot;&gt;Beta List&lt;/a&gt;: Discover and get early access to tomorrow’s startups.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://startupli.st/&quot;&gt;StartupLi.st&lt;/a&gt;: Find. Follow. Recommend startups.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.startups-list.com/&quot;&gt;Startups List&lt;/a&gt;: Collections of the best startups in different places.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.ycombinator.com/&quot;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;: A community of hackers from the team at Y Combinator&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://erlibird.com/&quot;&gt;Erli Bird&lt;/a&gt;: Where great new products are born.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/&quot;&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt;: Ok, you’ll have to know somebody&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve made it this far, you’ve completed something a surprisingly few have, despite the staggering statistics at the beginning. Be proud of yourself. And then continue marketing your product and providing outstanding customer service like your life depends on it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I have not failed. I’ve just found 10,000 ways that won’t work.
-Thomas Edison”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2015 11:33:39 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jakelarkin.co/blog/update/2015/03/03/recipe-for-app-launch.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jakelarkin.co/blog/update/2015/03/03/recipe-for-app-launch.html</guid>
        
        <category>Life</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Learning: The Unschool Method</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, I shared lunch with a very good friend of mine and over the course of about two hours we talked about nearly everything on our minds, but one thing really stood out. He was about to graduate and I am only a semester away from finishing school and we both shared the same feeling about what it meant to be a “college graduate.” An almost lack of enthusiasm. It seemed odd to the both of us that every semester, a few thousand students would walk away with the same stamp of approval from the university, but yet have drastically different experiences. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; makes an individual &lt;em&gt;smart&lt;/em&gt; and interesting? Is it the number of diplomas that they have or the number of courses that they have taken? Of course not. My friend and I both studied different flavors of engineering and as we looked back at the courses that we took in those four years, we struggled to even recall what some of them were about or why we were required (read: forced) to even study certain topics. This stuck with me. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why do we get college degrees? What is the relevance of what you study and the job that you actually secure? Most of the time, zippo. When a job posting states that a “BS is required,” it usually just implies that the company is seeking a candidate with a specific skillset, a tenacity to complete a long winded goal, and a personality to boot. However, that doesn’t come across on a resume. A diploma is a convenient categorization tool for recruiters to find employees when sifting through piles of resumes. But there is one big problem: employers require skills, not degrees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not suggesting that a college degree is not worth anything, far from it. The breadth of learning that can be accomplished while in school is incredible. Formal education is hugely important. Trust me, I don’t want a college-dropout surgeon who decided that medicine school “wasn’t for him” to operate on me. What I am suggesting is that there are distinctly different learning paths and both should be explored in depth. Learn new skills that you may not learn in school and do it not only because it may help you land a sweet new job, but because you will become a more well-rounded and interesting person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I encourage you to join me on a journey this year. A journey of learning, but not in the typical sense. Harness that inner curiosity that you typically silence for a fear of embaressment or failure. Let’s try a different type of learning. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;unschooling-yourself&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unschooling Yourself&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unschooling yourself is more a change in mentality. An eagerness to learn outside of the classroom or workplace. I share with you some suggestions that I believe may aid you in this process. Whether you are far out of school or still in school, these suggestions will still apply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;i-wish-i-could&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;1. “I wish I could…“&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have all been there. Envious of a friend or family member that has a skill you wish you had. Here is an often forgotten secret: you are perfectly capable of doing it too! Write these instances down and save them. Review them frequently and make strides towards achieving them. A very talented friend of mine has compiled a &lt;a href=&quot;http://youngisaac.typepad.com/creativity/&quot;&gt;few resources&lt;/a&gt; that may help achieveing goals. A very important aspect of this list is that it does not have to be related to the field of study or line of work that you are in. The process of learning new skills is highly non-linear and chaotic, which brings out a tenacity that will directly impact your professional career. Here is the list I made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; margin-bottom:50px; margin-top:50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/wish_i_could.jpg&quot; style=&quot;max-width:80%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;brag-about-your-mistakes&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;2. Brag about your mistakes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vulnerability is a natural fear of all humans. If you don’t believe me, a much smarter lady named Brené Brown can explain with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ted.com/talks/brene_brown_on_vulnerability?language=en&quot;&gt;her TED talk.&lt;/a&gt; Bragging about your mistakes seems counterintuitive, but when practiced you will see how impactful it can be. Be bold and reach for one of the goals you have listed. When you fail at it (which you will), tell someone close to you all about it. Simply sharing your story will release fear. You will be shocked by the support you get from your network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stop-comparing-yourself-to-others&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;3. Stop comparing yourself to others&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You remember that friend that you were jealous of? Just because they inspired you to learn a new skill does not mean you need to be as good as them at it. Be yourself and enjoy what you set out to do. Look at them for motivation, but never knock yourself for not being able to do as they do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;read-read-read&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;4. Read. Read. Read.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t stress this enough. Books, magazines, blogs, Twitter feeds, newspapers, whatever! Just read it. Dive into it and avoid the urge to skim. You may even find a few reads surrounding the goals you wrote down. Try using the internet productively, rather than aimlessly stalking friends on Facebook or playing Trivia Crack.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;write-about-it&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;5. Write about it&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout this journey, you should practice writing about your experiences. I began writing once a month surrounding three things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What went right last month&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What went wrong last month&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What I learned&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make this writing a habitual part of your life and it will hold you accountable to keep expanding your horizons. I find myself wanting to explore new things almost because I know I will have nothing to write about unless I do so. It is an accountability loop that you can produce all by yourself. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;just-show-up&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;6. Just Show Up&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saved the most important for last. This is the essential ingredient for learning outside of the academic environment. Two years ago, I had the opportunity to go to an event that I was somewhat intimidated by. An event called &lt;a href=&quot;http://startupweekend.org/&quot;&gt;Startup Weekend&lt;/a&gt;. A jam-packed weekend of learning the first steps of launching a startup, which I partially credit with the motivation that made me dive further into the idea of working at a tiny company. The people you meet, the things you see and the challenges you may encounter by simply stepping out of your comfort zone and showing up in an unfamiliar place with unfamiliar faces. This goes for pursuing the goals you wrote down above. Just show up…who knows what could happen!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-wrote-this-i-showed-up&quot;&gt;I wrote this. I showed up.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will leave you with a quote. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Don’t let schooling interfere with your education.
-Mark Twain”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 11:33:39 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jakelarkin.co/blog/update/2015/01/06/lets-do-some-unschooling.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jakelarkin.co/blog/update/2015/01/06/lets-do-some-unschooling.html</guid>
        
        <category>Life</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wait, why are you in grad school?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Why? It’s the toughest of the 6 interrogative words, but it’s the most important one to understand. The answer, whether realistic or not, provides a backbone to all difficult life decisions. It’s the one answer that you can firmly stand your ground with. And it’s the answer that ultimately makes up your mind.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In light of this, don’t simply ask that question of the world around you, but of yourself. And do it frequently. This is the story that brought me to Designli.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve always enjoyed learning. Building, tinkering, and rebuilding. That’s what defined me as a young kid. Engineering always seemed to be a natural blend of everything that was fun for me, so I came to Ohio State to pursue a degree as a mechanical engineer. Ohio State has one of the &lt;em&gt;coolest&lt;/em&gt; first year programs for nerdy engineers. For 6 months, they submerge you into the world of engineering design. A rapid learning environment with a lesson in drafting, CAD, C++ programming, data analysis in MATLAB, report creation, circuit design, proper testing procedures, and experimentation. Come spring quarter, this all culminated into the annual robot design challenge, which is essentially a quest to build the most badass robot that could &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=E4sgyj9rT7g&quot;&gt;autonomously navigate&lt;/a&gt; a course through a crafty blend of obstacles. I loved it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For most, including myself, this was a brand, spanking, new way of education. Learning by doing. I was in my element. Spending my days and nights looking through lines of code and throwing the robot onto the course for a 1500th time to guarantee that it would not crap out through certain turns and maneuvers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to the present. I am now a graduate student studying aerospace engineering at the same university. I run the entrepreneruship organization on campus and have launched a handful of &lt;a href=&quot;www.jakelarkin.co/#doings&quot;&gt;other organizations&lt;/a&gt; that reflect my passions. Beyond those, I am also a graduate research associate participating in research that will fundamentally change the landscape of aerospace design. Our lab is aggressively tackling problems that were previously unsolvable and the work done by my colleagues is incredible. It sounds like a dream job for an engineer, right? It was for me, until I asked myself the inevitable question: why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found myself stuck in a doozy of an internal conflict. Did I really enjoy being a full-blown research engineer? Beyond explaining to people what I did in the research lab and seeing them look at me like, “Whaaaaat..?”, the answer was no. I thought about everything that I had done in the past 4 years and &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; I enjoyed them all individually. I loved starting and building &lt;em&gt;stuff&lt;/em&gt; that &lt;strong&gt;actually&lt;/strong&gt; had an impact on the people surrounding me and beyond. I loved having a say in every part of the solution: engineering, branding, marketing, selling, hiring, everything! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plain and simple: &lt;strong&gt;Life is so much better when you don’t fake it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything that I was infatuated with pointed me towards entrepreneurship. The only thing that held me back was my prior perception of a successful career. I was nervous that if I didn’t go chase a career as an engineer at a huge aerospace giant, that people would assume I was too stupid to get there. I now realize how terrible of a mindset that was and I am rushing with excitement to begin my next chapter with Designli. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are reading this article, you and I likely have a shared interest in apps, startups or entrepreneurship. Since you have made it this far, I assume something I said has resonated with you. I want to dismantle some often proclaimed reasons to work in a startup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;you-will-be-ber-rich&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;1. You will be über rich&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, no, no. Nonsense. Is there potential for wealth in the future? Maybe. But that will come in the form of value creation and that takes time. In order to get anywhere with a startup, you have to be comfortable without a salary. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;setting-your-own-schedule-hooray&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;2. Setting your own schedule. Hooray!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You do get to pick your own schedule! Take any given day and choose which 14 hours you want to work! If you are starting your own business because you don’t like waking up early, then you’d be better off looking for a night shift. It’s not about the schedule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;be-your-own-boss&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;3. Be your own boss&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, yeah. You may be at the top of the leadership chain, but you can never avoid the feeling of someone telling you what to do. Whether it is your customer, your employees, your investors, or your mom…there will be someone telling you that you are wrong and that you need to do better. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More importantly, I want to share why I have decided to ignore the typical career path with an aerospace degree and work at a startup:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-product&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;1. The product&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Designli, we are bringing the joy of launching a fully developed app to customers that would have previously never been able to see their dreams built. Involving the customer in the process and helping them shape their idea into a tangible design. We are empowering customers to create something magical. It’s an exciting environment. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-process&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;2. The process&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you work at a company with 100,000+ employees under it’s belt, it’s only natural that you will be placed into a silo pertaining to one task or a set of responsibilities. For some, this is powerful because they can hone their skill and become the master of their craft, but I honestly could not pick a single skill that I would ever be comfortable doing that with. At a startup, you are not responsible for a task, but more so an outcome. However that outcome is built will be up to you. Chase it until you can’t chase anymore. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-people&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;3. The people&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is something about entrepreneurs. An intangible, unexplainable passion for what they do and how they are going to get it done. How they are going to change the world. Back in the fall, the Designli team took a visit down to Greenville, South Carolina to find a place to set-up shop and it was the first time everyone was in the same room. The conversations between these friends were no longer about sports or getting drunk at a bar, but about how the world will look in 20 years and where we will be. These are the visionaries that I want to be around. The real &lt;strong&gt;movers and shakers&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;remember&quot;&gt;Remember…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always ask why. It’s your backbone. I’ll leave you with this quote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“If you end up with a boring miserable life because you listened to your mom, your dad, your teacher, your priest, or some guy on television telling you how to do your shit, then you deserve it.
-Frank Zappa”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2014 10:33:39 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jakelarkin.co/blog/update/2014/12/08/grad-school.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jakelarkin.co/blog/update/2014/12/08/grad-school.html</guid>
        
        <category>Life</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Book Notes: Zero to One</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I was slightly skeptical when I first saw Peter Thiel’s Zero To One pop up on the pre-order list on my ever-growing Amazon suggested purchases list. I knew Peter Thiel as one of the master minds included in the PayPal Mafia and even more so as an early investor in Facebook, so I assumed that the book would be full of “silicon-valley this” and “san-fransico that” and plenty of other technical startup mumbo jumbo (is this a real phrase?) that fills the headlines of Tech blogs and Entrepreneurship magazines. I underestimated Mr. Thiel.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zero To One captured the essence of why the PayPal mafia was so successful without hammering too many PayPal specific elements. Thiel delivers just under 200 pages of forceful and crisp thoughts surrounding the true meaning of value generation. Most importantly, he opens up the economics book and discusses the impact that startups can have on the community we are building.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have snagged a few quotes from Thiel and share my own commentary on them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;zero-to-one&quot;&gt;1. Zero to One&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Doing what we already know how to do takes the world from 1 to n…but every time we create something new, we go from 0 to 1.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whoops. I just spoiled the meaning of the title, but he does this on page 1, so I am not that apologetic. This shined a ray of light on my outlook of innovative stuff - I now mutter this to myself when pitched a business idea. It’s so true…try this one on for size the next time someone pitches you an idea for the “next social network.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;start-small-and-monopolize&quot;&gt;2. Start Small and Monopolize&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Dominate a small niche and scale up from there, toward your ambitious long-term vision”&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is pretty apparent throughout the entire text. Imagine that you are the person that invented this thing  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; margin-bottom:50px; margin-top:50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/pillow_head.jpg&quot; style=&quot;max-width:80%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, you may be thinking to yourself, “Self, this thing is going to practically sell itself! Here comes my first billion!” I love the enthusiasm, but what’s the market? You’re cuckoo to think “anyone who sleeps on a plane” is actually a valid answer. I’d rather hear you say that you are going to sell it to your dad and your crazy uncle because neither one of them care what other people think of them in public. Start small. Prove that people actually crave your product and scale accordingly!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;founders-know-their-value&quot;&gt;3. Founders Know Their Value&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Okay guys, this is just a formality, it shouldn’t take more than 10 minutes. We’re obviously not going to sell here.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Name that entrepreneur! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; margin-bottom:50px; margin-top:50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/mark.jpg&quot; style=&quot;max-width:80%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yup, it was Mark Zuckerberg. In July 2006, Yahoo! offered to buy Facebook for $1 Billion. That’s 1000 Million Dollars…for a website that you likely didn’t even know about in 2006. Mark assembled his board members for a meeting to announce that there was now way that they were selling Facebook. Every investor in the room wanted him to at least consider the opportunity, but Mark instinctively knew that $1B was not even close to what Facebook could become in the coming years. A founder only sells their business when they have no more concrete visions for the company. As of November 2014, Facebook is worth $201 Billion. Mark knew was he was doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-mechanics-of-mafia&quot;&gt;4. The Mechanics of Mafia&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The startup uniform encapsulates a simple but essential principle: everyone at your company should be different in the same way - a tribe of like-minded people fiercely devoted to the company’s mission.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a cliché that startup employees wear the same logo-plastered t-shirts to work and around town, but the true meaning of that is much deeper. It may sound odd, but people’s passions come through in their fasion. For your startup to work, every person you bring on board has to be equally obsessed with what you are building, which will be obvious when you walk in the work space and see everyone sporting their favorite company hoodie or t-shirt. This may sound sort of Jim Jones cult-&lt;em&gt;ish&lt;/em&gt;, but there’s something to be said about a startup that only hires people completely intoxicated by the company. The only difference is that cults tend to be fanatically &lt;em&gt;wrong&lt;/em&gt; about something, while a startup is fanatically &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt; about something. I get a very similar feeling when I see another Ohio State student on campus wearing a Business Builders Club t-shirt!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sales-is-hidden&quot;&gt;5. Sales Is Hidden&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“If you don’t know any grandmaster salesmen, it’s not because you haven’t encountered them, but rather because their art is hidden in plain sight.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All through engineering school, I heard jokes about students who chose to pursue a business degree instead of an engineering degree. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; margin-bottom:50px; margin-top:50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/sales.jpg&quot; style=&quot;max-width:80%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To one extent, it is true - an engineering degree may take more hours cracking the books, but that has nothing to do with the relative skills required for generating value. As an engineer, you have the ability to judge another person’s work by simply evaluating if it works. It’s binary. Sales is quite the opposite - forging the surface appearance without ever changing the fundamental product. An engineer understands that their job is difficult and requires a lot of hours, so overhearing that the sales team took a client out to a three-hour dinner with drinks afterwards may be a bit frustrating. It may even seem like a waste of time. Thiel nails it when he says, “What nerds miss is that it takes hard work to make sales look easy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-seven-big-questions&quot;&gt;6. The Seven Big Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“If you’re at Tesla, you’re choosing to be at the equivalent of Special Forces. There’s the regular army, and that’s fine, but if you are working at Tesla, you’re choosing to step up your game.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thiel boils down his experience into seven critical questions that he investigates before any investment breaks his wallet. I will leave you with those seven questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Engineering Question: &lt;em&gt;Can you create breakthrough technology instead of incremental improvements?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Timing Question: &lt;em&gt;Is now the right time to start your particular businss?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Monopoly Question: &lt;em&gt;Are you starting with a big share of a small market?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The People Question: &lt;em&gt;Do you have the right team?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Distribution Question: &lt;em&gt;Do you have a way to not just create but deliver your product?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Durability Question: &lt;em&gt;Will your market position be defensible 10 and 20 years into the future?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Secret Question: &lt;em&gt;Have you identified a unique opportunity that others don’t see?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 17:33:39 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jakelarkin.co/blog/update/2014/11/24/zero-to-one.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jakelarkin.co/blog/update/2014/11/24/zero-to-one.html</guid>
        
        <category>Books,Startups</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
